Viewers all over the world, I say you are blessed.
The message: ONLY BELIEVE.
Tell your neighbour
ONLY BELIEVE
I can't hear you.
The Book of Mark 5:1,
"Then they came to the other side of the sea, to the country of Gadarenes.
And when he had come out of the boat, immediately there met Him
out of the tombs a man with an unclean spirit
who had his dwelling among the tombs; and no one could bind him, not even with chains..."
Physical combat. Listen to that.
"...because he had often been bound with shackles and chains.
And the chains had been pulled apart by him, and the shackles broken in pieces;
neither could anyone tame him."
Can you see how wild the crazy man was?
"And always, night and day, he was in the mountains ,
crying out and cutting himself with stones.
As soon as Jesus heard the word that was spoken,
He said to the ruler of the synagogue, 'Do not be afraid; only believe'."
I have no other refuge than this command of Jesus, 'Only Believe'.
I am talking of behalf of myself and my household.
I know you are one of them.
Listen to that.
I have no other refuge than this command of Jesus, 'Only Believe'.
If you are asking me, "How do you believe? Whom are we believing?"
If I believe you, it`s different from believing God.
You are here and God is a Spirit.
Can you see what we are talking about?
Here you are, and God is a Spirit.
If God is a Spirit, you must believe Him by the Spirit's power.
You can only believe Him by the Spirit's power.
By what? - By the Spirit's power.
Not just, "I believe you, brother".
It's different from believing in God because God is Spirit.
We must depend upon God's Spirit for our assistance and strength.
We must depend upon God's Spirit for our relationship with Him.
If I want to have a relationship with you, I will have it with you. I know you, I talk to you.
But to God, I must depend on God's Spirit for my relationship with Him
because God is Spirit.
How can we worship Him in Spirit and truth?
We worship God In Spirit and truth when all our purpose and passion of our heart
and when all our acts of worship - dancing, singing, praying -
are regulated and guided by the Word of God.
The question again: How do we worship God in Spirit and truth?
We worship God in Spirit when all our purpose and passion of our heart
and when all our act of worship - you know what I mean by act of worship -
singing, fasting, or meditating, "In Jesus' name"...
When all our purpose and passion of our heart,
when all our acts of worship - dancing, singing, praying, fasting, meditating -
are guided and regulated by the Word of God.
That is how we know we are under the influence of the Holy Ghost.
He does nothing without His Word.
He does nothing without what? - His Word.
We should be awake to the fact that we must believe.
If you can, all things are possible.
If you can, all things are what? - Possible.
Whenever we truly believe, our hearts will be at rest.
Remember, truly believe - I put truly.
Whenever we truly believe, our hearts will be at what? - At rest.
If our hearts are uneasy and restless, if we are afraid of this and that,
this shows that we have not yet believed.
When one believes, he is at rest.
When a person believes, he will no longer worry.
The kind of rest I am talking about is real, genuine and natural.
It is not a pretentious calm, unnatural self-restraint
or acting as if nothing has happened.
Let someone say, "Only Believe".
ONLY BELIEVE
I cant hear you.
We must believe and rest unconditionally and absolutely upon the Word of God.
Overflow Congregation
Take note: Faith does not rest in itself; God is the place where faith rests.
There is no faith in faith.
But faith in the finished work of our Lord Jesus Christ.
We do not need to force ourselves to believe that Jesus is Lord.
There is no need for us to struggle to believe.
This is the way with all kinds of faith.
Faith in faith, faith in this, faith in that.
If believers are not careful, they will be deceived.
If believers are not careful, they will be what?
They will be deceived because of their desperation.
Because of what? - Desperation.
When you are desperate, you don't mind where the solution comes from.
And you remember when satan was telling Jesus - he knew he was very, very hungry.
He took him up. He thought, Jesus was desperate.
He said, "If you can do this, you will be ok".
Jesus said, "Look, I am hungry but I am not desperate".
If believers are not careful, they will be deceived.
This is the way with all kinds of faith today.
When you are not living in the Spirit, you cannot live in the process of God's mind
and act according to His will.
But take note of this: We are to be sons of God with power.
Tell your neighbour.
[We are to be sons of God with power.]
Tell your neighbour once again.
I can't hear you.
[We are to be sons of God with power.]
We are to be born again with power.
We are to be evangelists with power.
We are to be pastors with power.
We are to be Christians with power.
We are to be prophets with power.
I don't know what you can be with God without power.
Because the Bible says, To be saved is to have revelation of the glory of Christ Jesus.
To be what? - To be saved is to have revelation of the glory of Christ Jesus.
And what is the revelation? - The revelation of God: 'Only Believe.' Thank you.
Whisper it to your neighbour.
That is why someone can be in America, South, West, North, Asia country and be connected with us here.
Only Believe.
That is why one does not need to come here before getting healed.
By revelation.
To be saved is to have revelation of the glory of Christ.
And the revelation of God: 'Only Believe'.
The work of faith is not a risk but a sure and practical act.
Do you see the way I grab it?
But it can be very, very risky if you have not received the message of the gospel of Christ,
if you have not received the promise of the Father, the Holy Spirit.
if you have not believed by the Spirit power,
forcing yourself to do such is indeed a risk.
When God comes to ask for worshippers, the question will not be,
"Who worshipped at The Synagogue Church Of All Nations?"
"Who worshipped at Jerusalem?"
"Who worshipped at that church or this church?"
But "Who worshipped in Spirit and truth?"
Tell your neighbour.
When God comes to ask for worshippers, the question will not be,
"Who worshipped at Jerusalem,
at The Synagogue, at that church or this church?"
but "Who worshipped in Spirit and truth?"
Because God is Spirit and His worshippers must do so in Spirit and truth.
But today, we refer to the Spirit, "The Spirit of God says this, the Spirit of God says that.
In the letter, the Spirit of God says this, the Spirit of God says that".
To how many does the Spirit Of God actually talks to?
The work of faith is not a risk but a sure and practical act.
Remember, 'Only Believe' - the revelation of God.
Rise up and talk to your heart.
Speak to your heart.
You have received so much and this message should not go without opening the door of your heart.
This message must open the door of my heart today.
Here I am, Lord, send me.
We believe you have been inspired by the clip you have just watched.
Click here to subscribe to witness more of God's power at work in our generation today,
and stay up-to-date with the latest prophecies, deliverances, sermons and testimonies
from The Synagogue Church Of All Nations.
Emmanuel TV - Changing Lives, Changing Nations and Changing the World.
TT Monica Asefa 27/08/18
RV: Mel Flowers 12/09/2018 + Robert